Irving B. Gerson papers, 1937-2007 and undated RL.11716
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Irving B. Gerson papers
1937-2007 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Gerson, Irving B.
RL.11716
23.0 Linear Feet
0.05 Gigabytes
Marketing executive and author based primarily in Chicago. Collection includes correspondence, autobiographical writings, research reports, short stories, manuscripts of memoirs and novels, clippings and other printed materials, as well as audiovisual materials (videocassettes, microfilm, audiotape reels, phonograph record) and electronic records on floppy disks. Topics include Gerson's work history in advertising, marketing and consulting; personal and family life; reflections on aging and career changes; and reminiscences of Gerson's experiences in the military during World War II. Companies represented include Elgin, Gerson Howe & Johnson, Hammond Organ, Irving B. Gerson Company, Robert Haas Advertising, Sears, W.T. Grand, Whirlpool and Young & Rubicam. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
1,903 Document files
Biographical / Historical
Marketing executive and author based primarily in Chicago.
Born 1919, Detroit, Mich. University of Michigan 1940; Harvard MBA 1941; U.S. Navy Reserve 1941-1945 (Bronze Star 1944); Gersons Jewelry Stores 1945-1953; Young & Rubicam 1953-1961; Robert Haas Advertising 1962; Elgin National Watch 1962-1963; Irving B. Gerson Company 1963; Gerson Howe & Johnson 1964-1979; full-time writer 1979-on; died 2009, Chicago.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: "My History" Binders; Other Binders; Subject and General Files; World War II; Writings; and Audiovisual Materials
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research; however, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced. Electronic records must be viewed in the Reading Room.
In addition, all or parts of the collection may be housed off site and must be requested 2 full business days prior to use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Irving B. Gerson papers were received as gifts in 1998-2010.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Alvin A. Achenbaum papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Dan Seymour papers
Marvin B. Kunze papers
Scope and Contents
Collection includes correspondence, autobiographical writings, research reports, short stories, manuscripts of memoirs and novels, clippings and other printed materials, as well as audiovisual materials (videocassettes, microfilm, audiotape reels) and electronic records on floppy disks. Topics include Gerson's work history in advertising, marketing and consulting; personal and family life; reflections on aging and career changes; and reminiscences of Gerson's experiences in the military during World War II. Companies represented include Elgin, Gerson Howe & Johnson, Hammond Organ, Irving B. Gerson Company, Robert Haas Advertising, Sears, W.T. Grand, Whirlpool and Young & Rubicam. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection contains electronic records that must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Advertising; Advertising agencies; Advertising executives -- United States; Marketing -- History; Authors, American; World War, 1939-1945; Gerson, Corrine Segal; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Young & Rubicam; Sears, Roebuck and Company
- "My History" Binders, 1957-1998; 1
  - 1. War, 1988-1992; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    99 Effects of World War II on One Almost Typical U.S. Navy Reserve Officer
  - 2 War, 1987; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 3. Gersons, 1988; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Me Before Business; Gersons through 1946
  - 4. Gersons 1947-1948, 1988; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 5. Gersons 1949-1950, 1989; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 6. Gersons 1951-1952, 1989; 3 folders (Box 1)
    With 1952 job search materials
  - 7. Young & Rubicam 1953, 1989; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 8. Young & Rubicam 1953, 1989; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 9. Young & Rubicam 1953, 1989; 3 folders (Box 1)
    Includes: The Real Answer to the Discount House Problem, 1953
  - 10. Young & Rubicam 1953, 1990; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 11. Young & Rubicam 1953, 1991; 3 folders (Box 1)
    Includes: Materials from Ohio Jewelers Convention, 1953
  - 12. Hammond Organ Company 1954, 1991; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 12a. United Air Lines, 1957; 2 folders (Box 2)
    The Air Transport Industry and United Air Lines' Place In It (for Young & Rubicam New Business Committee)
  - 12b. Fairs, 1957 (Box 2)
    A Brief Guide to Fairs as a Marketing Medium (Young & Rubicam)
  - 13. Elgin Watch 1954, 1991; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - 14. Young & Rubicam 1955, 1992; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 15. Young & Rubicam 1956, 1992; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 16. Young & Rubicam 1957-1959, 1992; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - 17. Young & Rubicam 1957-1959, 1992-1993; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - 18. Young & Rubicam 1960, 1993; 3 folders (Box 2)
    Includes: One Man's Philosophy of Marketing
  - 18a. Ledgers and journals, 1946-1963; 2 folders (Box 18)
    Includes: Financial planning ledger; job search journal
  - 18b. Young & Rubicam 1957-1959, 1993 (Box 2)
  - 18c. Young & Rubicam 1958-1959, 1993 (Box 2)
  - 19. Young & Rubicam 1961, 1993; 3 folders (Box 2)
    Includes: Young & Rubicam Five Year Plan, 1961
  - 20. Young & Rubicam 1961, 1993; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - 21. Robert Haas Advertising 1962, 1994; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - 22. Elgin Watch 1962-1963, 1994; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - 23. Unemployed 1963, 1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - 24. Irving B. Gerson Company 1963, 1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - 25. Irving B. Gerson Company 1963, 1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - 26. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1964, 1994-1995; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - 27. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1965`, 1995; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - 28. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1966, 1995; 3 folders (Box 3)
    Includes: Charles Percy campaign for Senate; Valerie Percy murder
  - 29. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1966, 1995; 2 folders (Box 4)
    Includes: Elgin Watch marketing plan, 1966
  - 30. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1967, 1995; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - 31. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1968, 1995; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - 32. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1969, 1996; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - 33. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1970, 1996; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - 34. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1970, 1996 (Box 4)
  - 34a. 1970 materials, 2 folders (Box 4)
    Includes: Waltham Watch advertising program; Catalogues, Counters and Offices (for Sears); Irving B. Gerson: Tomorrow's Advertising Agency
  - 34a. 1970 materials, 2 folders (Box 19)
    Includes: Waltham portfolio; The Story of Sears as Told in National Advertising
  - 35. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1970, 1996; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - 35a. Sears Marketing Plan, 1970 (Box 4)
  - 35b. Miscellaneous materials, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    Includes: Communications Program, Chicago Area Council, Boy Scouts of America
  - 35b. Miscellaneous materials, 1971-1972 (Box 19)
  - 36. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1972, 1996-1997; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - 36a. Miscellaneous, 1972; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Includes: Credit Marketing Plan (for Sears); The Plan, People for Percy
  - 37. Gerson Howe & Johnson 1973, 1997; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - 37a. Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 5)
    Includes: People for Percy post-election report
  - 37b. Sears Marketing Plan, 1973; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 37c. Miscellaneous, 1973; 3 folders (Box 5)
    Includes: Sears Credit Advertising Third Stage; Sears Credit test to young marrieds; Sears Contract Floor Covering marketing plan; Sinai Congregation 5-year marketing plan
  - 38. Gerson Marketing & Advertising 1974, 1998; 3 folders (Box 5)
    Includes: File on mother's death
  - 38a. Miscellaneous, 1974; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Includes: Sears Credit young marrieds' campaign; Record of Gerson Howe & Johnson involvement in Sears credit marketing programs
  - 38b. Miscellaneous, 1974-1978; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Includes: Sears Credit young marrieds' test; Sears telephone directory
  - 38c. Sears Contract Business Marketing Plan, 1974; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 38d. Sears CART marketing plan, 1974; 2 folders (Box 5)
    For Commercial Truck, Recreational Vehicle and Fleet Cars tire market
  - 38e. Gerson Marketing & Advertising 1974, 1998; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - 39. Gerson Marketing & Advertising 1975, 1998; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - 39a. K-Mart study, 1965 (Box 6)
  - 39b. W.T. Grant billing, 1975 (Box 6)
  - 39c. W.T. Grant, 1967-1975 (Box 6)
    Includes: Plans Board materials; questionnaires; Situation analysis; Study of Changes in Consumer Awareness of and Attitudes Toward Grants 1967 vs. 1966
  - 39d. Miscellaneous, 1975; 3 folders (Box 6)
    Includes: Grants marketing, financial and credit plan questions; Consumer Image of Grants and Competition
  - 40. Writings, 1976; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 40a. Gerson Marketing & Advertising, 1970-1978; 2 folders (Box 6)
    Includes: Profit-sharing plan, trust agreement
  - 40b. Gerson Marketing & Advertising, 1976-1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
    Includes: Profit-sharing plan, dissolution
  - 40c. Gerson Marketing & Advertising, 1965-1980 (Box 6)
    Includes: Minutes
  - 40d. Gerson Marketing & Advertising, 1976 (Box 6)
    Includes: Monroe Auto Equipment marketing plan
  - 40e. Betty Gerson memoir, 1976-1977; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 40f. Irving Gerson Writing to Betty Gerson, 1976-1989 (Box 7)
  - 40g. Miscellaneous, 1976; 3 folders (Box 7)
    Includes: Filter Plus report; Sears newspaper advertising situation analysis; Proposed Consulting Firm Analysis and Comments (to Robert A. Anderson); Grant finance file
  - 40h. Memoir of 1976, 1998; 3 folders (Box 7)
- Other Binders, 1937-2007 and undated; 2
  - 1970s, Money, Education (clippings), 1975-1981 (Box 8)
  - Air Transport Industry and United Air Lines' Place In It (Young & Rubicam), 1957; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - All critical and planning regarding my body of work, 2003 (Box 8)
  - Archives (correspondence, etc. with Duke University and other libraries), 1989-1998; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Assorted short pieces (writings), 1984-1994 (Box 8)
  - Business Journey of Walter Sanderson (novel) binder 1, approximately 1981; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Critiques, comments regarding my writing, 1980-1990 (Box 8)
  - Death of a Company, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Death of a Company (charts), 1981 (Box 19)
  - Draft of Walker marketing plan, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Embracing the Octogenarian Life, 2005; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Embracing the Octogenarian Life (Gerson copy), 2005; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Ethics, lying, business, robots, timing (clippings), 1961-1981 (Box 8)
  - Everything Is Temporary: Diary of an Octogenarian, 2002; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Faces: Backup material, 1999-2002 (Box 8)
  - Faces: Pieces considered, binder 1, 1937-2000 (Box 9)
  - Faces: Pieces considered, binder 2, 1984-1994; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Gerson Publishing Company, 1977; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Government, politics, lawyers, perspective, thinking, faith (clippings), 1972-1981 (Box 9)
  - Gravelings by Gerson, 2001; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Health, coping, diet, pleasure, sports (clippings), 1978-1981 (Box 9)
  - Hiroshima, Nagasaki and Waukegan (novel), binder 1, approximately 1985; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Hiroshima, Nagasaki and Waukegan (novel), binder 2, approximately 1985; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - How to Market Yourself Successfully, undated; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - In Reality, Life Is Similar to War Except Everyone Dies, binder 1: outline and notes, 2006 (Box 9)
  - In Reality, Life Is Similar to War Except Everyone Dies, binder 2: workbook, 2007 (Box 9)
  - In Reality, Life Is Similar to War Except Everyone Dies, binder 3: early versions, 2005 (Box 9)
  - Letters to Jan and Dee (writing project), 1981 (Box 9)
  - Letters to publishing agents, 1981-1986 (Box 10)
  - Long Range Marketing Plan (for Tenneco Automotive), 1979; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Marriage, divorce, family, love (clippings), 1980-1981 (Box 10)
  - Me and Advertising (writing project), 1973-1981 (Box 10)
  - Monroe Sales Department Plan, 1978 (Box 10)
  - More post-mortem material, 1980-1988; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Mr. Gerk Smith, MBA, Marketing Consultant, in the Case of "We Are Webster's" (novel), binder 1, 1983; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Mr. Gerk Smith, MBA, Marketing Consultant, in the Case of "We Are Webster's" (novel), binder 2, 1983; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Next Slide Please! The Story of Ronald J. Whitfield and Chartmasters, Inc., 1979 (Box 10)
  - Octo Irv: My Life After 80 (memoir): binder 1, manuscript part 1, 2003; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Octo Irv: My Life After 80 (memoir): binder 2, manuscript part 2, 2003; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Octo Irv: My Life After 80 (memoir): binder 3, notes, 2003; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Octo Irv: My Life After 80 (memoir): binder 4, outtakes, 2003; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - People, success, aging, advertising (clippings), 1968-1981; 2 folders (Box 11)
    Includes: Ronald Kushner autobiographical sketch
  - Personal public stock activities, 1961-1974 (Box 11)
  - Pieces (writing projects) binder 1, 1979-1999 (Box 11)
  - Pieces (writing projects) binder 2, 1980-1992 (Box 11)
  - Pieces (writing projects) binder 3, 1949-1989 (Box 11)
  - Pieces of a war novel never finished, approximately 1940s (Box 11)
  - Publishing efforts, binder 1, 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Publishing efforts, binder 2, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Recap, 1943-1986; 2 folders (Box 11)
    Includes family correspondence and reflections; drafts of writing projects; journal entries
  - Redbook (Standard Advertising Register) entries, binder 1, 1952-1963 (Box 11)
  - Redbook (Standard Advertising Register) entries, binder 2, 1964-1977 (Box 11)
  - Religion (clippings), 1975-1981 (Box 11)
  - S.R. Fisher, Businessman (novel) binder 1, 1981; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - S.R. Fisher, Businessman (novel) binder 2, 1981; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - S.R. Fisher, Businessman (novel) binder 3, 1981; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - S.R. Fisher, Businessman (novel) binder 4, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Second Career: Businessman to Writer (memoir) binder 1, 1988; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Second Career: Businessman to Writer (memoir) binder 2, 1985-1990; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Second Career: Businessman to Writer (memoir) binder 3, 1988-1999; 2 folders (Box 12)
    Includes commentary,critique from Corinne Quint Siegel
  - Secret Opinions, binder 1: Xlibris version, 2000; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Secret Opinions, binder 2: People, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Short stories and other fiction, binder 1, 1944-1994; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Short stories and other fiction, binder 2, approximately 1937-1993 (Box 12)
  - Think Piece on Sears' Next 10 Years and What Whirlpool Should Do About It, 1979 (Box 12)
  - W.R. Grace marketing plan, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Whirlpool project, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Writing, change, death (clippings), 1960-1981 (Box 12)
- Printed Material, 1925-2001; 3
  - Harvard Business School Yearbook, 1941-1942 (Box 12)
  - Irving Gerson: A Key to Successful Marketing, undated (Box 12)
  - Irving Gerson: Be Big Somewhere and Other Essays on Marketing, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Irving Gerson: Gravelings by Gerson, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Irving Gerson: Secret Opinions vol. 1, 2000 (Box 12)
  - Irving Gerson: Tomorrow's Advertising Agency, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Marriage Record and Hints on Housekeeping, approximately 1925 (Box 12)
    Gerson's Jewelry Store ad on p. 8
  - Martin V. Marshall (Harvard Business School): Marketing notes, OPM class 20, 1992 (Box 12)
    OPM: Owner/President Management Program
  - S.R. Bernstein: The Lasker Story As He Told It, 1953 (Box 13)
  - Whirlpool Strategic Planning, 1983 (Box 13)
- Subject and General Files, 1937-2001; 4
  - Advertising, 1981-1999 (Box 13)
  - Aging, 1979-2001 (Box 13)
  - Be Big Somewhere--Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1975-1977; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Business, 1940-1999; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Change, coping, 1981-1988 (Box 13)
  - Communications, 1982-2000; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Culture, 1980-2000 (Box 13)
  - Education, 1981-1999 (Box 13)
  - Entertainment, sports, 1975-2000 (Box 13)
  - Ethics, 1979-1999; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Geography (predominantly Chicago area), 1974-1996 (Box 13)
  - Gerson Howe & Johnson documents, 1964-1994 (Box 18)
  - Government, 1979-2000; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Guide to doing plans (transparencies), undated (Box 18)
  - Happiness, 1959-1987 (Box 14)
  - Health, 1981-1999; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - History, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Humor, 1977-2000 (Box 14)
  - Love, 1979-1999 (Box 14)
  - Love--Responses to Gerson's personal ad in New York Review of Books, 1981 (Box 14)
  - Marketing my writing, 1986-1989; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Money, 1981-1999 (Box 14)
  - People, 1980-2000; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - People--Mary Cunningham, 1980-1984 (Box 14)
  - Philosophy, 1984-2000 (Box 14)
  - Race, 1979-1981 (Box 14)
  - Religion, 1982-2000 (Box 14)
  - Sex, 1937-2000 (Box 14)
  - Success, 1979-1999; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Technology, 1983-1999 (Box 14)
  - Thinking, 1980-1999; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Time, 1986-1999 (Box 14)
  - War, 1944-1995; 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Work, 1977-1988; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Writing, 1981-1996; 2 folders (Box 14)
- World War II--Gerson's military experience, 1941-2004 and undated; 5
  - 87 Effects of World War II on One Almost-Typical U.S. Navy Officer, undated (Box 15)
  - Gerson Bronze Star (clipping, photos of award ceremony), 1944 (Box 15)
  - LST 349--Shipwreck photos and narratives, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Minesweeping operations, 1946-2004 (Box 15)
  - My Own Experiences of "The Wreck" (LST-349), 1944 (Box 15)
  - Naval Mine Warfare School class album, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Navy discharge papers, 1945-1953 (Box 15)
  - Navy documents, 1941-1985 (Box 15)
  - Poem--The Splinter Fleet, approximately 1942 (Box 15)
  - Short stories and other writings, 1942-1987 (Box 15)
  - Sicilian Close Shave (story), 1945 (Box 15)
  - Silent Defenders (newsletter of Naval Mine Warfare Association), 2004 (Box 15)
- Writings, 1957-1994 and undated; 6
  - Be Big Somewhere and Other Essays on Marketing, 1977 (Box 16)
  - Brief Guide to Fairs as a Marketing Medium, 1957 (Box 16)
  - Business Journey of Walter Sanderson (novel), approximately 1981; 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Don't Worry, Dear, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Hiroshima, Nagasaki and Waukegan, 1980s; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - How to Market Yourself Successfully, 1982; 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Letter Three: America a Sick Society?, undated; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Little Old Lady of St. Maxime, 1945; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Monty, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Mr. Gerk Smith, MBA, Marketing Consultant, in the Case of "We Are Webster's", 1983; 4 folders (Box 16)
  - My Bronze Star, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Obesity Is Not All Bad, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Pedro and Reverend Mary, 1984 (Box 16)
  - S.R. Fisher, Businessman, 1977-1979; 4 folders (Box 16)
  - S.R. Fisher, Businessman, 1977-1979 (Box 17)
  - Second Career, 1984 (Box 17)
  - Second Career, Businessman to Writer, 1994; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Secret Opinions of Irving Bernard Gerson, 1985-1987; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - The Toaster Cover Maker, 1984 (Box 17)
  - Tomorrow's Advertising Agency, 1970 (Box 17)
  - Will of Irving Gerson, 1994 (Box 17)
    Includes draft of gift agreement to Duke University
- Audiovisual Materials, 1967-1998 and undated; 7
  - Microfilm roll 1: Journal, 1976-1978 (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11716-F16-001)
  - Microfilm roll 2: Journal, 1978-1980 (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11716-F16-002)
  - Microfilm roll 3: Journal, 1980-1982 (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11716-F16-003)
  - Microfilm roll 4: Journal and Novel, 1982-1984 (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11716-F16-004)
    Includes: Journal 19812-1984; Fisher first and section sections
  - Microfilm roll 5: Novel, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11716-F16-005)
    Includes: Fisher third and fourth; Letters to Dee and Jan; How to Market Yourself Successfully; Gerk Smith; Hiroshima; Sanderson
  - Scouting makes a boy a better man--radio spot, approximately 1973 (Box AV1, Audio-phonodisc RL11716-PD-001)
    For Boy Scouts, Chicago area; lyrics Dave Adam; music Joe Eich; side 1 Joe Eich singers; side 2 instrumental
  - Mrs. Gerson eulogy, approximately 1998 (Box AV1, Audio-reel RL11716-RR-001)
  - Samuel Gerson, Dr. Hertz, 1967 (Box AV1, Audio-reel RL11716-RR-002)
  - Samuel Gerson eulogy, undated (Box AV1, Audio-reel RL11716-RR-003)
  - Gerson in Person, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11716-VHS-001)
- Digital Materials, 1945-2002
  Series disks contain text files of Gerson's manuscripts including personal journals and diary; Elgin, Gerson Jewelers, Haas, International Business Group, and Young & Rubicam companies; and Duke journals and manuscripts. A majority of the disk contents are incomplete due to degrading 5.25 and 3.5 floppy disks.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Collection contains electronic records that may need to be reformatted. Access copies of electronic records must be accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services for access.
  - Diary Manuscripts, 2002; 13 documents, 1797KB (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)
  - Duke Journals and Manuscripts, 1964-1999; 201 documents, 201KB (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)
  - Elgin Manuscripts, 1994; 8 documents, 355KB (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)
  - Essays and Second Career, 1992-1994; 50 documents, 1491KB (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)
  - Gerson Manuscripts, 1963-1964; 0 documents, 0KB The file title is base on disk labels. Contents were unable to be recovered during processing. Further attempts to recover data may be made. Contact research services for more information. (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)
  - Gersons Jewelers, 1945-1952; 38 documents, 1191KB (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)
  - Gravelings Manuscripts, 2001; 37 documents, 1770KB (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)
  - Haas Manuscripts, 1994; 0 documents, 0KB The file title is base on disk labels. Contents were unable to be recovered during processing. Further attempts to recover data may be made. Contact research services for more information. (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)
  - International Business Group Manuscripts, 1963; 0 documents, 0KB. The file title is base on disk labels. Contents were unable to be recovered during processing. Further attempts to recover data may be made. Contact research services for more information. (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)
  - Journals, 1985-1994; 1360 documents, 29.7MB (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001, Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0002)
    Access restricted. Collection contains potentially sensitive medical information. Contact Research Services for Access. https://duke.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_8fblaT2NbgbQujj
    Separated Materials
    RL11716-SET-0002 contents are separated due to sensitive medical information.
  - Young and Rubicam Manuscripts, 1953-1990; 196 documents, 4924KB (Digital-materials RL11716-SET-0001)